[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
my mates
welcome to the junker love podcast
today's recommendation of something else
to watch is Jordan green Hall deep code
the documentary and that is on the rebel
wisdom YouTube page it's an interview in
conversation when Jordan green off great
perspective on the state of the world
check that out definitely worth it in
the meantime I hope you enjoyed this
conversation this one's with Brandon
Cruz we did it over a video chat as I'm
kind of trying out video chat and trying
to keep the podcast plugging along in
the best way that we can it's not as
good it's not as connective as an
in-person conversation but we definitely
got to some great subjects he actually
kind of he has his own podcast and the
format for this one was kind of him
interviewing me so I kind of have an
opportunity to go into a little bit more
depth on some of the concepts that I
work with and some of the concepts that
I am still kind of creating and
conceptualizing but but I think they
could help a lot of people or hopefully
somebody so let's get rolling with the
podcast if you're listening to this
right now and you have not drank water
in the last 30 minutes what are you
doing man drink some water
enjoy hit record I am recording oh hey
okay
the bong lip town will be the intro it
should be I'm gonna I'm in a little way
and wider flick it do you think awesome
thing to do yeah
three two
well that sounds so nice though the
whole thing it just catches up in
fighting if you put a cop in and you rip
a ball well it subside the coughing
mm-hmm I'm gonna test that theory right
now it also gives you a form of lung
cancer from the menthol so oh I want to
just dump a whole pack of cough drops in
my bomb and rip it you can see if it's
like this is the obvious he'll probably
surprisingly delightful it probably
would taste so good - yeah bong water is
absolutely gross but cheers mate I'm
such a puss with punks
[Music]
I'm not surprisingly tastes really good
oh man what's going on Jacob Ryan's
hello buddy
hi this is a wild productions brain and
cruise with wild for deductions taken on
all things media and apparently bong
related today we're talking with one of
my really great friends
Jacob Ryan's who has dedicated his life
to music production sound design and
creating music and also being an
inspiration to the people as far as
mental health and just being an absolute
badass for people in life and just
giving them something to wake up for and
an inspiration to bounce back from the
depths of a dark mind Jacob Ryan hello
man thanks for having me this is cool
I'm not a good intro for you I feel like
I've done a little bit better but I mean
I think that's good you know it's so
difficult to describe yourself like in
in one sentence in one paragraph in one
podcast like afterwards
like what I don't know like what do I
represent I'm kind of I'm kind of
circling in on my on my like life quest
you know like there's gonna be this one
sentence like I want to stand for this
and I believe in ending the suffering of
humanity you know like there will be
some sort of end goal but I I think I'm
still circling it I have my hands and
interest in so many different things at
the moment do you have a life quote for
yourself at the moment I don't know the
word resilience popped into my head just
now but I don't know I I I believe I
don't know I guess I believe in I wrote
this thing the other day I just spit
ball off Tom my head it was on my
Instagram but just about believing and
magic and believing in dreaming big and
believing in yourself and believing in
spirit and believing in like the the
greater good of humanity just just if
you have to change the background when
you say that background when you say
that yeah space one person I believe in
cycling the earth on the planetary orbit
ridiculous I love having this option
it's so cool it you look amazing space
in my space outfit from space Jesus
[__] that's a good rap yeah I don't
know there's there's already an EDM guy
that space Jesus and he's he's killer oh
yeah I was like the photo of space Jesus
was floating around space or is there
actually like no he's like an actual
like EDM guy I think I love that like I
love this makes good other names they
want it sounds so cool - I mean like
life quotes are cool but could you
imagine walking around and everyone
calling you space Jesus would go to my
head absolutely that would be amazing
I'd have a huge ego bigger than I
already do is it first name space last
name Jesus or first name space last name
Jesus like a sprained ankle [__] I'm
not a nothing Jesus you're
you can't walk on me yeah you can't walk
all over me
we're always just writing raps I
actually you and I have written some
some rap together for fun I think it's a
great outlet actually I wrote two days
ago I had this loop that I made it's
like first thought that I had and I was
like cool let's just go with that and I
record it looped it and I sat down here
for probably two hours and just got like
just one page that's all I got two hours
but it was a less to like write a song
and more to you know kind of like just
work through some stuff like sometimes
you don't know what you think yeah they
start writing it down and and I think
it's also fun we've done it before -
yeah it's it's definitely a different
Avenue of thought and thinking I think
that goes like with any sort of art form
you're like oh I can't use my like
everyday thoughts to try and figure this
thing out especially with rap you're
like I mean the beat is there and you're
just like I have a blank book to just
say absolutely anything I want the hell
do I want to say and no it's cool I
definitely I definitely want to try to
get into that a little bit more and just
kind of experiment just for like art's
sake and just taking a break from the
everyday art form that weird so
accustomed to right but how I never I
don't think I ever asked you how did you
get into the arts and being an artistic
person and how did this all come about
um well I think I well well back even
with in middle school I had an interest
in acting that probably sprouted it I
had this teacher this language arts
teacher who was also the drama teacher
and I just thought he was the coolest
person and he just he just liked music
and he liked we had like a play that we
did we yeah and so I did it I did plays
and then I've always just kind of been
into like music after that I was I was a
big Walkman kid I just always had
headphones on I liked all kinds of means
so that inherently leads you into like
more artistically thinking I suppose and
then as I grew older in high school I
was in like acting classes and stuff and
in drama
I enjoyed acting there but I was also
social too and so I don't know I think
that's where DJ come in it's weird
because I feel like I have an artistic
side mm-hmm but I also have like a
social side in there like not super in
Herring or balancing but yeah well it's
so weird because the amount of time that
you spend creating is like quadruple the
amount of time socially talking to
people being like an actual person
yeah like [__] I go like eight days I
can or I can go like eight days straight
eight hours alone in my office and just
like be fine oh and then and then
someone's like hey I want to hire you to
DJ a 300 person party you're like holy
[__] I haven't talked to anyone in eight
days yeah I got obtained some people if
there was four in here I know I'd be
uncomfortable they're all just staring
at you to like for some reason they
don't all stand together even if there's
four people that show up they're all in
different areas of the room feels like
you're just like they're shouting at me
yeah and if they're having a good time
it's still weird
each other just at me yeah just you yes
and they ask you questions to ask the
other people instead of asking them each
other they're just like the middleman
and all this thing this is so
uncomfortable I feel uncomfortable just
thinking about have you ever been
thought about as like it's so weird but
not necessarily as the person like if
I'm in a club and there's like [__]
going on like I'm I'm feeling myself I'm
around all these other people and then
you go up to the DJ like requesting a
song or something like that I don't know
if people do that now or whatever but I
got done it before like went up asked
them to play this
which I know is kind of annoying
sometimes but for a DJ but when I see
that him I see them is like not a person
but like an element of like what is all
going on do you ever feel like that I
don't know if I explained it right but
yeah yeah it's kind of like the the
narrator of the story
the if if there was let's say if there's
an alien in space let's but there's
another quick if there's an alien in
space and he's looking down he's got a
telescope perhaps and he's looking
through and he could see the party like
the building and there's no roof on the
building and through him the alien up
there he's like looking down kind of
observing this mm-hmm at this level so
there's the the people in the crowd as
they're moving throughout the night
through man I feel like I went too far
when I was talking about the alien part
no I feel like I get that analogy more
than like okay so essentially I'm
controlling you know I'm controlling the
vibe like I'm not at the party I'm not a
part of the conversations I'm not I'm
controlling where the conversations may
go so I'm I'm kind of sitting above all
the vials I'm not just looking out for
what songs I want to play personally
like my ego itself my eye by who I grow
up as my interest my personality is like
those play a part in it but at some
point I kind of let go of that and I
allow it to be this other sort of being
that's floating above and kind of like
kind of taking a glance and like
listening in like what's what are these
six people in this booth talking about
okay talking about that what are these
six people who just walked in wearing
okay they're wearing that they're this
age and what's their energy and what's
their tone and stuff like that like what
and what time of the night is it also
because that like you can play the exact
same thing at 11:30 p.m. that you played
in you can try that on Friday and it
goes off and then you play the same
thing at 10 p.m. because you did
a little too early on Saturday night and
it's a total nobody even stopping their
foot so I'm in place certainly so you
you kind of have to create let go of
your your interest kind of influence you
and that's kind of what builds your
computer what builds your sound what
builds you your library your crates like
that's the crates that the DJ comes with
is kind of his playlist and he's basing
his playlist off of like okay here's my
style and here's what I know I'm
probably gonna see tonight but then as
the night progresses you're like oh okay
there's this kind of people here tonight
I was expecting more of of the older
crowd so I would have played this sort
of thing but instead you're kind of
sitting back and trying to observe what
people's fives are if they're trying to
get buck wild enough and I'm just hang
out and it's just I think that's why
it's so surreal is because you literally
from like our perspective we're like
looking up at a DJ and they're like just
getting down like getting in the flow of
like the actual music but then also
they'll like look up and you'll just see
them like like interacting with the
crowd and realistically you're like oh
yeah you guys like the [__] yeah you do
let me see what do you guys what I say
next even what I'm whispering do you
guys like this mom hey watch this [__]
mmm you guys like that [__] don't you
and then everyone goes yeah and then
you're just like god damn I'm going back
to it and it is just the coolest thing
ever like seeing that like you're
playing this calculated game on top of
five and out and like doing your craft
as well - it's so cool it's a your
strategic looking from yeah it's kind of
like a meta cognition of like you're
kind of leaving your body in a strange
way like as you're trying to like like
you're not trying to interact with the
individual people you're trying to act
with or interact with the vibe of all
the people different things and
sometimes when someone comes up that's
why sometimes even just someone
requesting is enough even if they're
nice and it's a good request it's enough
to pull you out of that like from way up
here like a flow state yeah so
but but it's hard because you know
there's different parties and different
different vibes and sometimes you got to
show up as someone who is in their
headphones the whole time just mixing
and doing your own thing and sometimes
you got to show up as someone who's you
know a quarter of the time you're you're
leaning in and in getting the getting
the person on the other side is paying
you so you're doing what they want you
to be doing and these are different
assets you have to earn or facets of
DJing that you kind of have to like the
difficulties that you have to maneuver
through instead of like I think it's so
funny the average person the average
person and the average creator usually
have this interaction I don't know how
many times in a creators life but
they'll come up to you and degrade your
work based on like simple knowledge like
they could literally be like what's the
problem you can't take the picture I can
push a button on a camera and take a
picture it's like it's not that simple
man like and then you try and walk them
through it and they're like so what you
like flip the few girls you flip a few
girls all the time and then take a
picture I could do that too mmm and it's
just like oh my god you guys have no
[__] clue there's no clue and you
make one up just mmm don't live for one
of these it doesn't happen often but
when it does it's one of those special
moments where you're like you really
don't know [__] about this dude it's not
sorry go well it's the lack of awareness
after a while like people being able to
step out of their own shoes in a way and
have awareness of a different type of
person that thinks differently than them
and and truly knows more than them so
like if you're not willing to admit that
like hey like I am I I am the the
foreman at this lumber mill and I'm a
badass and people listen to me and I've
been the boss for 13 years and I know my
[__] so you should listen to me because
you're just a dumb photographer yeah
when you're too caught up in in your
your rewards and your your titles when
that's to attach to what yourself is
when
you approach someone in a situation
where they're completely different than
you you are comparing your knowledge to
the knowledge that you think you know
about them no they think they know about
photography and so they're like do I
know everything about photography or a
good enough amount to know that I'm
smarter than you so they're gonna come
at you as is like a taller than you
person looking down right and so it's
almost it's almost like you they I don't
know I don't know I suppose I suppose
they just don't see eye to eye lately
you just kind of have to assume that oh
yeah this person they're not actually
insulting my camera abilities they just
actually they literally have not learned
they haven't took time to learn
throughout their however old they are
fifty four years of life that how to
understand people on a different
emotional level how to look at people
introspectively how to UM how to not
they haven't learned the skill that you
have to be able to see like oh you're
just a different person who
misunderstands me it's not as simple as
you think it is mm-hmm not made much
sense but now that makes a lot of sense
but how do you I mean everyone at some
point or another has gotten themselves
and that experience whether it be
creating or not just a a dominant person
trying to diminish you with a certain
persona with creating and with being a
DJ have you had to face those people and
did you how did you handle it basically
like did you use more aggression or did
you just like step back and be like it's
not even worth my time like I'm just
gonna get beyond this then move forward
I mean sometimes like that like there's
parts where like sometimes I'll be a
little cocky like I've also improved
over the years I started heating up a
DJing for for I don't know eight nine
years or something like that so I've
improved just like my ego not like
having such a quick reaction so I have
had
times where someone has been rude in in
there just just being immature and like
I get to where I'm like someone needs to
make sure this person knows that their
actions are not okay because if they're
doing this to me
how do they treat like a Starbucks
worker or you know a grocery store
employee I just kind of really wonder
and so I have had experiences where the
I was playing a couple songs as I was
mixing I started to notice that like the
person on the dancefloor was literally
like going like this he was booing he
was thumbs down he started going boo boo
boo next song next song and you know it
was because he didn't personally like
that song and I was like I was like
giving him kind of a look and then
eventually it boiled up quicker than it
should've and I cut off the music
completely and I was like excuse me and
I had like this sort of like you realize
you're not the only person here there's
plenty of people in this room yeah that
are just as welcome as you are to be
here essentially he like got very
embarrassed started kind of like arguing
back and then it turned out no he threw
him out this is like not a big deal but
it was sort of like I punked him and so
I've done that and trying to like
brought him down and so that that's like
a huge ability that a DJ has like turna
a building on a person which is like
kind of kind of cruel but it's big all
right and then like who's being mean to
Jake you know I like cuz it's a it was a
local place that yeah yeah yeah but so
that's kind of like a there's there's
some parts of you that sometimes need
those excuse me it seems as if you're
not understanding your place like it
seemed as if I'm sorry you're talking
down on me sir I believe that you're
treating me as a jukebox I'm forgetting
that I'm a human you know
what would some some people take
different things to learn those sort of
things sometimes a drunk person who is
like telling you about this thing and
telling you about that thing and telling
you what you're doing wrong or in your
face or the or you say please no no I
will not take that request or no I can't
do that please leave a lot of strangely
something that happens a lot with drunk
people is you tell them now and they
they don't compute their brain says what
and they stand there in front of the DJ
but like they
and their interest you know and they
look right at you like I'm like typing
in and I'm going to this happens off
this is weddings as bars this is private
events like what drunkies I'm not
kidding this aviso kind of not a normal
thing like it happens every night but
when this happens when you tell people
no in whatever way in so I'll reiterate
so that was one example that I gave or I
turned off the music kind of dorky kind
of egoic right mhm it felt great of
course it felt great stroke here you go
but uh there's also a point of just
leveling with them and just looking like
so I've had times that weddings were
like an older person is like you this is
not acceptable you cannot play this and
I've had to be like sorry sir listen
this was a special request from your son
I dunno I would love it if you didn't go
over to him and try to dukkha this out
essentially I was playing uh I think I
was playing an afro man song at a
wedding later in the night in the there
wasn't communication between the person
who requested it which is the groom he's
paying me it's his wedding I'm playing
and of course no in like someone's
father someone's uncle something like
this and he was angry he's like it's not
acceptable for you to play this like
were just very very mad and I had to
meet him with please understand the
situation mm-hmm I the person who is
paying me the person who I've had
contact with I've never met you in my
life you're just telling me that you're
this person that's me today is is so so
you are saying what you want is more
important than what the person who is
paying me so it's kind of this like
breaking of a barrier again like I have
to be I have to I have to stand up for
myself as a person but I also have to
represent myself as a business that's my
own business and then I also have to not
cause this bigger eruption this bigger
problem of sending this this guy who's
angry about the song I'm playing over to
the groom who's wrapping his face off
with his best friends from college on
his own wedding day you know yeah like
so it's it's a it's a strange dynamic so
it's you know it seems like it's it's
just music right but if you are if
you're really paying attention here
you're kind of trying to hold
everybody's everything
in an intact and give everyone a little
bit of what they want and just keep the
fire going yeah it's just like it's a
it's crazy how people will confront you
with confrontation like they will
literally walk up to you I
that's never made any sense to me for
some reason I don't understand how you
can not know someone absolutely at all
and for this instance a song starts
playing that doesn't resonate in your
head but it resonates elsewhere you
literally come up to a stranger with
like hostile demeanor and say like hey
you need to shut that [__] off like
what's like who are you yeah and it's
like how do you how does that from this
point to that point is there any
justification for that or like it have
you known people that are like that or
like they're they're lost in the maze
they're lost in their manes man they're
like I said sometimes you could say
something sometimes it could be dramatic
sometimes it could just be like hey
listen it seems as if you're having a
problem being told no right now and
that's enough tip for them to be like
whoa like their momentum stops like this
wall it's like oh [__] like they're so
in their head like I'm gonna do this and
I'm gonna tell him this and I'm gonna
whatever like what we have momentum on
that thought they identified themselves
with that thought and they got momentum
with it and then which to me is being
caught in your own maze of sorts in
somebody else's maze like go tell him
that this song sucks yeah this song
sucks because you just grab onto someone
else's maze that they come for you and
so often times just I don't know that
there's that there's an excuse for it
but I think that being able to realize
that you're caught in your maze so if
someone does say like hey like so if
someone came up to you and they're like
hey can you
like you're standing in the way you're
an idiot like you what do what do you
think you're doing you're not supposed
to be back here like they're just like
insulting you and like what do you like
to do and you're like excuse me instead
of saying no no Susan said that I can be
back here like instead of doing that
instead of interacting with the the maze
coordinates that he told you to meet him
at mm-hmm
you you look above the maze you look
into the maze you in not looking down on
him but you look at the situation you
say oh it seems that you had sir it
seems that you have a misunderstanding
of who I am and by that I mean I am
actually the photographer I have
permission to be back here I'm totally
not in your way I can step over to the
side like you can kind of tell him like
no no I'm the photographer I have
permission to here whatever and then all
of a sudden instead of just fighting
back with him and meeting him at his
coordinates at his and his battleship
coordinates yeah sitting down at the
point he's about it play the game push
the button yeah let's get oh really push
that button no give him don't give him
the don't let him push the button you
know like link don't give him the button
to push of yours just just instead say
oh okay I see what's happening here
you're just confused
he's a don't say this guy is inherently
a dick because then all of a sudden you
have to fight you have to argue with a
dick in the other argue with a dick so
don't tell yourself that he's inherently
a dick say oh he must be stressed too
because his daughters getting married
because he's he's the owner of this club
and it's not busy or maybe he's stressed
because he is this first day on the job
and he's actually seen the security
guard and he was told that no we slept
back here and here you are no you got it
you can't just assume that someone's a
jerk you got to assume that like look at
the situation like there were
circumstances that play yeah
and it's yeah it's a training you could
do you see those situations in front of
you and you end up laying the path for
yourself to do the same later I think
that's what's so cool about you and your
way of experiencing the world and really
taking it in on Instagram you're
constantly posting inspirational videos
quotes posts you're talking yourself
about ideas that you have
a lot of them go along with the lines of
like that temperament and like checking
yourself also like just being very
consciously aware of what comes out of
your mind what comes into your mind and
I don't know you've just done a bunch so
it's it's a it's really cool to see that
you have a great way of implementing it
in your life and so it then begins to
resonate with people and makes sense
like you literally be like I was
thinking the other day that I was at a
gig and some dude came up to me and I
had to check myself and be like hey
maybe he's had a rough day or maybe
something's going on and you meet him at
a place you kind of guide him to a place
where it's like how can you be mad at
like a dude so calm and chill and like
it you you actually are controlling the
situation by toning it down instead of
not having control of the situation and
toning it up you know it's it's because
if you were to get angry you'd literally
be playing on his level he's already mad
he came up to you Matt so that's his
like yeah you're in his meds dude so
tone it down and throw them for a
curveball be like whoa like make them
realize that damn I am a dick if I'm
getting mad at just like just show
person you know this person was coming
at me just like a friend basically you
know so it's it's really cool to see
that from you and just to see you not
only talk about it but actually just in
a minute
shoot I'm going to stop and start this
real quick no I thought that was dude I
thought for a second that that was like
a home phone I think it was a maybe it
was there's this thing that reminds me
of time yeah okay change the space chain
two space one two every time the timer
goes off we have to take it I forgot
watching that 30 minutes every 30
wonderful joy right too many enough
chips
as we do we the stores are open god damn
my phone sucks so bad sorry I was just
saying that weed stores are open it's
kind of like I know it we still have
this like silly demeanor that's kind of
hanging on weed I can't wait till it's
fully shaken off I get that it's kind of
it has a silly vibe to it that's okay
but it is cool to see that weed stores
like like who'da thunk like 10 years ago
sounds like hey bro there's gonna be a
pandemic but during that the weed stores
are gonna be open you like weed stores
do groceries hospitals we had and that's
what's so funny about like reading these
Facebook posts and whatnot it's just
like people people are literally being
like I don't know what I would do if I
didn't have weed right now
I'm getting so high and just like taking
a nap or doing whatever they're just
they're just trying to exist right now I
like just yeah and if I can be with
yourself from ahead and being with
yourself sometimes you got to get a
little stoned sometimes yeah it just
allows for a I mean obviously anything
you do has an effect and if you do it
like non-stop all the time and that's
the way you live your life and it's
gonna start taking its like negative
precautions but like that's your choice
to do smoke weed like 24/7 and sit down
and pick your belly button and like
[__] videogames like dude you and I
think about like sorry you're gonna say
problems just I was just gonna say I get
[__] stoned and like it's so creative
in my mind and I'm just like stories and
[__] playing my head and I'm like oh my
god like I could film all this and I can
do you know whatever goes on it's crazy
that a lot of people waste their time
and their creative ability when they
smoke on like other [__] that distracts
them from what they could be doing and
it's just
it's crazy because you can see
creativity in people by the way they
talk and by they articulate by the way
they articulate themselves and you'll be
like damn brolic you can describe a
story in my head so well like you could
be a comedian you know or like you
described a story so well you can
probably take some video of it like just
learn how to record video and like the
idea is all you need it's it's not the
the art of learning how to control the
camera or the camera or anything like
that it's once you learn how to control
the camera what are you gonna do with
that control and that is like what the
art is and so I feel like people get
intimidated with the physical like
knowledge of how to do something beyond
the fact that like everyone has to deal
with that and once you know that like
it's it's no knowledge you can't like
picking up a guitar and just find it
again like now you can begin to explore
like everything like all your
possibilities in your mind it's just
weird to see I know you're a very uh
inspired person and a very dedicated
person in creating content and creating
art and like getting what's in your
brain out and so it's like it's just
really cool to see you when I go over
your place like we'll find out for like
eight hours and literally like blink and
good what the [__] what did we just do
well we created a song we did a podcast
we like you know played the piano or
like made some beads so like just
whatever it is I'm like damn that's nice
that's like right and we we could just
kind of vibe like that so it's really
cool to see that and do that do you
think that it seems a little silly you
know like I think like like to be grown
man like because that seems like some
17-year old [__] like you know like get
baked Oreo or even not yet baked like
just just hang out yeah have a beer or
come over have food and then also just
take a few hours and just like grow like
I was working on this little jingle and
start
clean it for them like oh okay all right
you just have to it like it you know
like those those moments of kind of you
know we call it childlike because that's
the comparison of how we think we need
to live in society mm-hmm versus like
that's the only thing we can think of
that makes sense mm-hmm in that box but
it's kind of just like creating and just
kind of freely vibing and allowing your
friend to freely vibe and allow them to
fully like like them knowing that you're
never gonna judge them or make them
it'll make them feel weird for like just
suggesting like hey what about this
mm-hmm really just letting opening that
flow that we have such a constriction
too that we that were taught to squeeze
and like don't let that flow and make
sure you tighten up and make sure you're
polite and make sure you don't say this
thing on accident like letting that
thing just unfold amongst a friend that
you trust I think it's kind of this
childlike play but it's also this just
spirituality really it's just feeling
it's a it's a it's a self-love it's a
it's a flowing of who you really are
like when you're creating like that
because you're not really having
standards for yourself you're living in
the present you're you're you're not
trying to be anything you're just kind
of just letting it happen in front of
someone too so that's very no it's it's
just odd because it I think the oddness
and it comes from like it takes a lot to
be able to create it takes a lot of
owner abilities out of you like to
express what is in your mind and know
that others may not perceive it the way
you do and you just have this anxiety of
like oh my god like what will they think
if I say that this verse should be in
the song or say that they should change
their piano to this sounding or whatever
it is like it's very it's just super
scary for a lot of people and I think
that's what's so weird about like being
able to go over and kick it with you
it's like we can go for like eight hours
and like I feel 100% just chill and fine
and knowing that like any thought that I
have is like not a degraded thought it's
a thought to get to another part of the
project they're part of whatever it is
it's like I think that's what people are
so scared of I think it is this
judgmental by that other people give
each other because it seems so weird to
me that a lot of people can't spend like
eight hours with another person it
doesn't have to be eight hours five
hours three hours but they can't spend
that amount of time and create but they
could spend that amount of time play
video games and like kind of do mindless
things that take their mind away from
like having like actual like very
intimate like creative things happen you
know what I mean like it's it's not
intimate in like a weird way it's
literally like intimate and it's like
you are literally giving yourself as a
creative mind out to the universe and
having another person at the same time
like check it and see like hey maybe you
could do this maybe you can do that
maybe we can do this maybe you know you
come in here and come in here like it's
it seems so weird that it's so abnormal
to have that deep human interaction with
others well what do you what do you
think like so yeah I was just thinking
about like like two homies who are are
hanging out like online playing video
games mm-hmm they're both like yeah
they're hanging out but like they're not
really like like you know occasionally
maybe they're talking crap they're
talking about the game like they're
inserting themselves into the game and
like hotting you shot me or a hole okay
I got that guy you head over here like
they're they're in the game they're
they're making up like I guess you could
say maze again this one isn't like a bad
one I suppose that's how they're hanging
out like they they're making like maybe
a third person that's in the video game
or a third version of themselves or
something that's not in the third
versions of themselves are interacting
in the video game they're kind of shut
off mindless just like and their fingers
aren't there in like a lull you know
yeah yeah and then but but when you're
mephone someone else's directions so
you're doing what the video game
creators have you're within only the
limits the box
the the you can't step outside of the
video game like as you're shooting in
world in this war game you can't not
only have like kirby can't all of a
sudden come in your view but you also
can't have like your mom walk into the
video game like it's not physically it's
not possible your yeah other thing
that's been created for you so therefore
it has boundaries right so you're locked
within the boundaries but you're still
having a companionship with someone so
it's great that's a cool thing I pointed
out for a reason I think but and then
you look at hanging out with someone
like just say what we're doing or what
we were doing just creating so we're we
do have I guess confinements in the same
way right like whatever piano or
whatever instrument I have whatever
tools were given whatever influence we
have had that day like we're all kind of
locked within those sort of levels but
we are able to when you are on that you
and I are being creative we're able to
kind of create a third mm-hmm and it's
in that same way like we're not as
confined we're kind of tapping into
something a little more pure to each of
us and we're both like in like hey like
what do you think about this in before
I'm done saying this and like you'd be
like I love that I totally get that
League um yeah it's it's this weaving of
trust for another human yeah it's but it
but also it's like I like to think of it
as like the avatar references like put
plugging the hair in is like when you
create with someone else you're
literally like plugging into this third
beam and like connecting and they're
connecting from their side and it's like
channeling like everything together so
you guys are both no matter what it is
that people do like when they create
with others they all get into this flow
state and that's what's so enticing
about it like if you're in a studio with
people and there's like five of them and
they're all working towards creating a
song it's like five people just like all
in one just synched up I'm all together
in this flow state and it's just crazy
yeah like it like a band they do you
ever take photos or videos for bands
I have yeah I have before oh yeah you
tell you literally have hero said yeah
so so you've seen it like you like where
they get on this they're not saying
anything their mouths are only speaking
in lyrics and you know humming and stuff
but their fingers yeah in there so so
they're not actually saying anything I'm
not sign languaging they're all in their
own zone but they're looking at each
other like okay and they said a million
words like they they're creating almost
another vibe which we can say is the
band's name right like so there's three
people Jake Jake and Eric and together
they create roast ham but what is roast
and yeah it's a band but you know if you
really want to want to try to understand
what it what it really has the capacity
to be you can look at it as a separate
separate sort of thing a separate thing
you know this love them that has a
separate entity you know and then what
did you come up with that like the third
idea because I've heard you say it a
bunch of times and every time it
resonates is like as the situation comes
how did you come to that insane thought
yeah it was weird I was reading I was
reading all the crazy books I think it
started I was I was incredibly depressed
for a lot of years and I was starting to
get better and I was starting to like
like fight back sort of like this sort
of like your life sucks and everything
that happens to you and you deserved all
sudden I started creating this like
voice that was like no [__] stop no you
know in in you know I think I look for a
lot of people what would that what that
is maybe they've lost touch with their
or they're like confused which forces
what but I think for a lot of people
that maybe like spirit like like they're
they're godlike so say if you're born a
Christian family that like when you're
feeling sad you know God's always with
you and try to think of this like so I
heard this voice and it was it was God
and he said everything's gonna be okay
like my understanding is that we create
that we create however we can understand
that but my backed up understanding is
kind of we created ourselves like from
personality and our experiences and some
breaking point whatever so essentially I
created this kind of like
like like caregiver I suppose right like
a like a there's consciousness yeah
another person mm-hmm yeah like a I in
through that I don't know I so I was
reading I was reading I was reading some
strange books and I was reading I think
a book called psycho cybernetics and
that was super interesting in it it
started making me like realize that you
kind of have an observer of your
thoughts like there's like like so what
what I had done at first is try to
create like I am the depressed self like
that's why I felt like I am very
depressed I'm I'm wearing this ugly mask
like I am I'm this like depressed person
and in and then so through that I was
able to create this thing like all of a
sudden I had this like you know what
yeah you're depressed I'm just
expressing but start saying no start
saying but you could be better but you
can get better you can make better
choices you could help yourself more you
can whatever like so that created kind
of a second and I started kind of having
this like with my depression I started
having this like argument I guess like
sounds the sounds strange they sound
like different people my Hedley sound
like different voices they're totally
not that it's just not like that yeah
it's so I started having this just like
when I have a depressed thought I'd had
have this like person who would stand up
for me and it was like me like it was it
fell fickle it felt fake for weeks and
maybe even months it felt stupid I felt
dumb I felt embarrassed but I was down
here by myself
nobody did judge me but myself and so I
just kept it going and be like you know
what no you feel better or not fix my
posture and then so over time I started
learning more reading more books I
started kind of like really
understanding what I what I was dealing
with more in realizing that I'm neither
the depressed person nor the person that
is saying no don't be depressed but I am
the observer of those two thoughts mmm
and it allowed me to really kind of I
suppose step outside of of what was
happening in my mind and my body and and
and kind of not not feel the need to not
only feel at one stage or just feeling
that I was the depressed thoughts and
then my stage up from that you know the
the foot step up the staircase of
healing the path I stepped on a you know
a tough guy a guy with some boxing
gloves he's like gonna fight nut
impression in that that did help me for
quite some time it helped me get brave
and build my comics back up and work on
my masculinity and and stand up for
myself and in whatever but then
eventually I came to this this other
let's say third who is the observer of
these things of watch instead of all the
time when like okay I have a bad thought
time to like fight with it and say no
that's not a bad thought like whatever
why don't you just watch both of them
happen to not interact with it mm-hmm
and that was that that's kind of my
third and that's kind of how the
observing mind works and that's when I
think that's that's when I first came up
with the concept of the third but as I
was conceptualizing I was listening to
jordan green and in daniel shmatte and
Berger there's it at ten times fast man
he's a massively yeah he was just on air
Eric wine Stein's
the portal podcast yeah yeah man he was
just on that one oh it's so good but
anyway so I was listening to them and
then so they started talking about the
concept of circling and they were
talking about kind of I don't know I
they were talking about if they didn't
directly reference it
I apologize for skipping around here but
I'm getting to the point yeah if they
didn't directly reference it what they
were talking about was I think it was
Jordan green made me realize that kind
of when you're podcasting you kind of
create a third as well like how I was
creating the third observer of my Jake's
superhero super Capeside mm-hm I awesome
future self versus my depressed bad
thoughts I'm worth nothing self doesn't
have a fight
there yeah when I created this third
it's a little bit like when I'm having
this podcast when I'm talking you know
we're talking and we're very deep in the
into it into a conversation you know
when there's these people here you're
looking in their eyes you're talking
about what they're talking about you're
in agreements you're kind of filtering
each other's sentences together it's
it's braided right but but also as I'm
talking I'm like hey and listener if
you're forgetting here's where we're
talking about this thing that means this
I'm also grabbing the listener and the
listener is the third and the listener
almost kind of like keeps you in check
right like this is kind of how some or
something the concept of God some
movement the concept is you know I if
you're looking for spirit I suppose I
can kind of fit in there but that's just
being too broad but um essentially the
listeners of a two-person podcast are
your third mm-hmm yeah I think maybe
that's it so I don't over explain it
maybe I should just end the explanation
right there I got it it's going on in
such a heart I was just gonna say it's
such a hard concept to like try and
portray because a lot of the times it's
it has to come to you I think you did a
really good job of actually explaining
it to because you made it very simple to
trying to understand from a viewpoint
what it's like but a lot of people can't
grasp it because they they can't they
haven't had the feeling of like putting
a second or a third in their mind and
using that to counteract whatever
negativity or whatever doubt you have in
your life like people don't understand
the potential of this that you can give
yourself an alter-ego in your mind that
is an idea of the best version of
yourself and when situations come you
literally say like damn I don't want to
go to the gym right now mmm
in my mind like Zakk Wylde's with love
Jack Wyatt in the gym right now already
like he's [__] getting huge like it
sounds crazy but
why is it crazy if it works for your
life like nobody jumps in your mind and
says like you're [__] weird you talk
to another person in your mind like
never I'm thinking about the idea of the
best version of myself mm-hmm I named it
this you don't have to name it if you
don't want to do but just know that it's
an idea that you have in an option to
become the best version of you if you
really want to listen to it it's crazy
because you're constantly everyone knows
you're constantly in a battle with
yourself all day every day on the
simplest choices like the idea of a
consciousness does not wow anyone like
you all hear the little voice in your
head right that's crazy enough like
that's crazy that it a voice that has no
sound but you can understand it and it
tells you what to do in situation
situations gives you urge is to do them
this way like mm-hmm
it's a random voice that gives you the
easiest route creating a second creating
a third not only can stray you away from
that continuous easy thought it can give
you better thoughts but it can also
understand the situation that's going on
in the third sense and analyze all right
like what is going on right now mm-hmm I
can either eat this cheeseburger feel
like absolute [__] or I can like work
for like ten minutes and make a salad
and like eat way healthier like this
simple stuff as that it's like are the
hardest decisions for people to make in
life like overweight people literally
will will have the thought of eating a
salad but the temptation and the sound
in their head but they hear the loudest
is like just eat this cheeseburger you
know it's so good you know you don't
need it but you are where you are
already what's the point of like eating
another one it's fine you're you are or
where you are you haven't lost 20 pounds
so you can use that conscience sound and
create another one to be to beat voices
in your head it's it's insane but like
the route that you're on
is infinite as far as helping people to
get over some of the hardest humps in
life that they can possibly imagine
and it's it's nuts that it can come down
to a a voyage that you created in your
head it's the possibilities are infinite
I'm not saying walk around the town and
[__] said I'm blah blah blah and I'm
the strongest [__] person in the
world Leia it's it's it's not like that
and that's what people view it as it's
like gods chill out and just think for a
second right yes you just gotta stop you
can become a where yeah just become
aware of this just I don't even ask you
to say anything in response yeah if you
don't like it you can get up when I'm
done and walk away but just think for a
second just listen don't talk alright
hit him with that and then you know it's
it's just hard for people to grasp but I
feel like it's impossible to explain it
unless they just like AHA awaken to it
one day yeah I think sometimes sometimes
we can what seems to happen a lot of
times with thoughts like that I mean
even even becoming aware that you that
you're thinking not not thoughts
observing thoughts you're like oh [__]
like who's wait who's observing the
thoughts but you you know even just that
is something that's so new to people
yeah and it's a it's almost I mean it's
almost scary you know what right it's
almost it's almost unnerving but that's
just you know that's your kind of say
egoic mind trying to protect you from
change because change is you know you're
safe in your cave exactly how you are
you know you're going want you to
continue to do the things that you know
get you happy like the instead of you
know instead of like setting up all the
things that and going to the store and
getting all the fabrics and in getting
all this all the arts and crafts
supplies you need to bring back home and
have a date night with your girlfriend
you could get the same amount of like
dopamine from just sitting there on your
phone and scrolling like in your brain
kind of knows that like you don't
conceptually understand that so it's
just like we've just been trained to
take the easy way out because as of our
just I suppose our generation like it
and I don't know if this is really just
news I'm gonna turn believe it all in
just phones but cuz Amazon's cuz uber is
because post mates it's cuz all this
[__] it's on the way to really do all
that [__] really well we've gotten food
yes [__] whatever we want really
really well like getting everything that
we could ever need to happen right now
it is the first time it's the first time
in human history that we have never had
to hunt wonder where our food is and
have it actually like not even hunt for
it at the grocery store like we can
literally have it sent to us in our home
like our others reversed now we have we
have things we have animals in packages
coming to us yeah right and hunting this
[__] that is so like human history could
you think of that as a species human
history you're exactly right like think
about it if you're looking at like a
timeline of like okay back in the 10th
grade when you're learning about the
history open the book and it's the whole
thing all the way across okay this is
when this happened and then okay and
then the influenza and the Great
Depression and then the coronavirus like
thank you literally like you right now
are going to be on one of those lines
one day biking for in a couple hundred
years like whatever their version of
books are you're going to be like that's
happening right now understanding that
it's like it's it's just nuts just
making about history now more than ever
is like we are in one of the most
special times in human history as far as
like evolving into something that is
like it's like what do you do if you
don't have anything to worry about
anymore you know what I mean like what
is the human potential
we take away all distractions and we
just all we got to do is focus on work
what can we work to improve the human
body or the human just the human being
in general we're gonna give you food
we're gonna give you shelter we're gonna
give you everything you need right
shipped to you immediately when you need
it what are you gonna do to help the
human race become this like it's like
what what do people want the human race
to me is the thing like nobody's asked
like anybody what they want it to be
they're just like hey we're just gonna
keep progressing until we just become a
[__] robot essentially like we're
like but yeah we don't want to change we
want to still keep that beating heart I
think everyone who keep that mind we
want to keep that mind but let me tell
you this what if I gave you a microchip
in your head you can still think if now
you could think with the internet and
it's just like that sounds cool yeah
like the whole [__] world is just
clapping it like oh yeah right there
like it's gonna bluetooth to your iPhone
your iPhone is now your mind it's like
this [__] is you and it's like that's
literally leave the direction we're
going in and everyone is [__] jogging
with their eyes open like all the way
they're not missing this weird to think
like who are you without your phone like
if you like exactly who you are now like
it like whoever whatever the concept of
I self me you your name like who you
live by who's on your birth certificate
whatever like that person who would they
be if if if they never got a phone like
whether it would this scenario could
nobody ever had phones oh I got a
positive real quick the scenario could
be if you never had phones or it could
be that like you just never got a phone
and everybody else around you did like
who would you be like think about our
interest where it were influenced the
things that we buy we're we're
identified with you know a lot of times
our look things that we buy sometimes
are sold to us because they're suggested
to it as we're scrolling through whoever
has the most money is selling that and
putting that in front of you it's just
interesting we I just I just wonder like
like when we connect to our you know
intuition when we connect to our like
ourselves like our knowing are like you
know are we are we really more than not
only our influences around us and our in
our the data that like big companies
have on on us and and how often we're
being consumed by as we consume all this
all of this electronic wonderful stuff
who are we I don't know before that are
we somebody different like without our
influences of being grown up being
raised by the people around us and kind
of just influencing being influenced by
them and kind of repeating what your mom
and dad and older siblings did in some
certain ways and like you kind of watch
this guy and kind of review this like
that is you in so many ways but also is
there something that's more you than
that mm-hmm are you born with a you
before any of the influence like wow
that would but you is created based on
your environment you know what I mean
and based on their circumstances and
like it being with no circumstances at
all it's like there's an infinite amount
of views that's why there's like
trillions and trillions different
versions of you is because life is so
split into every every possibility
exists at once you know what I mean so
the you without any of these influences
is just like nothing you know it just
depends on what path that you took
and so but I understand that what you
mean when you say like if you got if you
took your phone away
you'd be a completely different person
like if someone threw you in a jungle
and like left you with a spear and said
like survive
you'd be a totally different person like
we're all just a product of our
environment but at the same time like
guys you do have control over how much
time you're on your phone and how much
time you're like it's just like
literally spending on this [__] and like
giving your undivided attention to it or
something else you can change like who
you are as a being it's just by simply
putting your phone down and realizing
that like holy [__] it's there laying in
my bed for 30 minutes scrolling I
could've hit the gym I could have taken
a shower I could have whatever like
which leads to something else which
leads to something else and you can
literally split your path into the best
you that you want to be just by being
consciously aware that hey I'm on this
[__] a lot and a lot of people are on it
a lot but it doesn't mean that I should
you know so it's right what do you think
about what do you think about I feel
like right there is where I always
wanted in certain knowledge for me like
I just like knowledge and learning new
things is just so important as it's like
I don't know just just being at that
point in realizing right there is where
you're like okay like I got to start
learning more so I can empower it's like
the better self like he's got to get
smarter he's got to get wiser he's got
to start taking care of himself as if as
if like you are like a father out in the
woods and all of a sudden you have to
like take care of a kid like you don't
how to take care of a kid but now you
have all the tools at your hand it's
taking it like you can search whatever
you want you can read whatever books you
want to like you can adapt and so
essentially I think I don't know I just
it's self-improvement seems like this
thing like a hobby but I think that it's
something that should be everybody's
hobby because it's improving that voice
it's it's taken that that tough voice to
the gym and then after a while you start
to kind of realize I think that that
like the the knowing that knows that
this is good for you and knows that like
you deserve the selfless
anyway is kind of like the intuitive
something-something it's just is there
it's just so nuts is because a great way
to grow yourself excuse me great way to
grow yourself is obviously to grow your
mind and like learn just learning new
things having different thoughts like
just having a different approach to life
is learning it's not just like opening
up a textbook in like reading this low
love knowledge that you're supposed to
bring in like you have to look at
everything as like okay like I'm eating
healthier that's growing because I'm
becoming knowledgeable and aware of what
I'm eating and now I'm getting healthier
and um now I'm more susceptible to even
grow knowledge is knowledge in its own
you know what I mean so it's just
depending on the way you look at it but
it's just so weird is because we've
literally gotten Adam's apple you know
what I mean Adam and Eve's Apple of
knowledge like we can go on the internet
and look up anything in the world at any
point in time immediately like you're
reaching into like the world's mind and
like [__] just alright get whatever you
want it and and we're all so dumb
innocent we don't we don't understand
that we must godlike powers go ahead
like right now literally one person can
kill everybody right now like as easy as
right now you can go there's a mother
another mother [__] can go in like
maybe not immediately kill everybody but
like he could send I'm not saying
there's a magic button link Dexter's
labora yeah I resolve missiles but that
there is there is a form of like so we
have so much power as a human species
now that we could like end all of this
like you could fire this which starts
this guy to fire back which starts this
country to fire back and it starts or we
all die whatever it's just
and I forgot where I how I jumped to
that analogy on that one I don't know
but we did we missed a bummer for this
session remember I deposit we forgot it
I'm kind of scared at the moment but I
promised myself that for the people for
the people that go do this for you you
got it you got a entertain the people
when I'm gone I gotta go look I really
have to pee too these people we're just
gonna have to well I'm just I'm just
gonna chop I'm just gonna chop this
little middle part right here in three
two one boom shot oh you just sent me
another picture of your puppy that's
okay yeah it's [__] cute dog brother
have your life is gonna change man yeah
I'm super hyped attack dog you look good
drama - actually what what kind of dog
is it specifically he's an Aussie Doodle
oh my god yeah today I don't think they
shed no no yeah oh because I got rally
genic Oh everybody eats dogs
you got lucky man yeah man I'm sorry I
mean like it's so crazy it's so crazy
like like we keep just like looking at
photos and like we'll text each other
I'm like you know I think do you
remember that we're getting a dog and
it's only been three days since we put
the deposit I have like 27 left to go so
but we're just we're so excited like our
life is just super ready for it and I
feel like you know when you know it's
kind of like yeah yeah I'm trying to
have that feeling about having a kid cuz
I'm 24 still don't have a kid thank God
and I'm trying to hope that one day I'm
like you know what I'm ready
yeah yeah that is my goal one of my big
goals in life and yeah you know I
haven't had to swear but I feel like
I've more recently inserted it into my
head like you know like dude you do want
that so trying to like allow allow the
thoughts to populate yeah like trying to
tell myself that - that one day the
circumstances will be good and like
maybe they won't be but just know that
I think you are ready whenever but I
mean you're always gonna figure it out
link yeah always
yeah but that's just just can't think of
that right now that seems so insane to
have a kid to have a kid do that [__] is
so moving your best for a kid is it's
crazy to think about when you like
really actually just think about doing
your best in general what does that
really mean we get it we got to hit one
for the future kids right now
I suppose this one's for you baby if
it's a girl or if it's a boy all right
I'm gonna go to the beach um me and I
really look like the guy who smokes a
lot of weed damn well is the tie-dye
shirt man I think you just you just gave
it away and the that beanie is taking on
like it orangish like pinkish hue from
the lights so you really like it just
radiating right now but are you seeing
me on the other screen I mean let me put
your big screen real quick the beach
after this I am so dead serious I really
want to go to the beach yeah we should
we should literally take a trip when
everything opens up I can give us a
little bit of time but like we should
plan on like just a quick like cally
trip or like some beach trip somewhere
cuz bro I'm down I mean that would be so
dope we can even plan a trip have you
have you guys done like seaside Long
Beach like have you got that story yet
yeah yeah we we've went there estate at
Lincoln City oh yeah that's everywhere
it was cool so yeah but yeah if we do
that if we do that that would be so much
fun and it's it's really easy to it's
like two hours away yeah we could do to
it like but we could also do is just and
say we could even go down as like a
cheap night
for me and you or me I need to get some
creation done like let's get some
content let's like get some [__] written
let's like [__] let's go out and film
yeah let's let's leave the house with
like a list of like alright we gotta at
least get these things done like so it
so it's kind of like a work trip but
also because like we have so much fun
we're creatively working but kind of set
some rules around assets and boxes and
boundaries around it and we could just
go down to like a story and [__] get
some like crappy hotel and just go to
the beach and get drunk at midnight but
but bring a notepad you know it's sick
yeah like where I like where your head's
at but yeah hell yeah that's the beanie
of knowledge right there the biology the
blockage that ecology how do you uh we
can wrap it up soon cuz I know life is
happening but how what I wanted to ask
you is how do you believe that someone
can start like getting smarter and
attaining knowledge because it is it's
such a hard thing to like pick back up
like either reading or like just
studying some sort of something in
general like like how do you think a
good way is to like start implementing
or like start getting back to like a
consciously learning mind I guess I
think I'm definitely willing to share
how I did it but I also would say before
that is is when I guess I did do this
learn how you learn how you learn you
know especially now you don't have to be
diagnosed with like ADHD not not good
memory or not being able to focus or
like you'll just notice that things that
you don't have a ton of interest on if
you're not getting paid to do it you're
not gonna pay that much attention to
it's just kind of like our brain has
been given so much [__] stimuli that
we're just we it's just how it is which
is buzzing hard yeah so so just learn
how you learn and here's what and I'll
give you my personal examples that maybe
this doesn't work for everybody but so
so what I mean by that books I used to
read so many books when I was young I
loved reading books I was like the get
you're like read I was like a step of
like whatever book the class was gonna
read I had already read
like I love like reading with the Harry
Potter books like up until four I think
was out when I was in school Lord the
Rings like I just loved getting into
these fantasy worlds and I was like when
I first started I was dude I want to
bring reading back like that I was like
I know I used to love reading readings
good you got to be reading and I
realized that like I have no way to sit
still like I like can't sit still I was
like ADHD and I start obsessively
thinking about things like I can't seem
to just sit down and read a book like I
would try and try and try and try and
try and so I was like well I'm not
giving up I'm not just gonna say well I
guess readings not for me
my brain has developed and this is it
and sitting in the sand because that's
just not what I agreed to do like you
know like I said when you when you build
that third that that's strong other or
that you know that strong other self
with steps in the ring that's a tough
guy he doesn't take no for an answer
right so you so I was like okay so the
old way that I was learning the way that
I used to read the way that everybody
else seems to read doesn't seem to be
working out like I want to read that's a
huge thing that unlocks all the doors
right like once you can like make
yourself sit and read 19 hours a day or
one hour a day or whatever amount of day
yeah acha door into all this knowledge
right so but I couldn't seem to learn I
couldn't seem to get this childhood like
joy of getting lost in the story to
where I can't have my foot twitching and
I can sit for longer than seven minutes
yeah it is I I bought the book that I
was trying to read about it on audiobook
and I put it in my headphones and I went
for a run I kept running and I set a
goal before I started running as a
finish this [__] book and I came
running and so I finished it and this is
just now I really do this is crazy I
live extreme sometimes because I need to
like push past these he's mr. Hyde so
yeah it ain't you know you know better
thought so I I ran and it's like 14
miles or something and I and I finished
the audio book this book was profoundly
great it was like a it was a book on
steven pressfield's the war of artists
on resistance so it was literally like a
voice in my ears telling me about
resistance and how I can beat it so oh
my god
audiobooks and so don't like rocky yeah
oh no I
yeah and that's things you got to like
Iraqi like it's born to it what would it
feel like to believe that I'm rocky
right now you know sort of things so I
think learning how you learn and so
learning how I learned is in never
taking no for an answer like so what
what I've learned is that I'm to this
point I'm great at I'm a daily meditator
crate up meditation almost just said
that what a silly thing to say but I
made often and I'm able to sit still in
those moments but I still am not super
able to absorb knowledge and read so
reading again what that taught me when I
when I ran and read that audiobook was
like okay running and reading audiobooks
that's an option also there's a ton of
lectures and things that I can list you
without watching on YouTube that's an
option to do while running while going
for a walk and my headphones and so I
started kind of adding these things up
like so how can I consume more books and
how could I learn more and so I started
down here adding on to that I would put
it on my speakers out here and I would I
would let it play or get all the vibes
right get all the smells where I could
all the the lines right and I'm like
okay I'm gonna read this for an hour I'm
gonna read this for whatever read this
try to set a little goal for myself it's
like a beautiful reading experience but
no it's one just set it all up and I
know it's like a silly thing to do
money-wise but if you really want to
like if this is that important to you if
your future later on it's more important
to you so I would get I have a couple
books that I have the audiobook version
that I would let play and I also have
the physical copy you know today with a
highlighter and I would paced back and
forth because ADHD and I can't seem to
sit down and read a book but I would
like yes stone sometimes that helps me
just kind of like be able to relax and
pace back and forth and listen to the
audiobook as I either take notes and
stand on the bar a or I highlight as
it's oh that was pretty profound and so
I don't get all distracted to go write
the down or I need to go home I don't
know it it keeps bringing me right back
and when I'm like okay I highlighted so
it's it's learning how you learn right
like so over the years I've adapted this
like crazy can't sit still whatever like
so I thought that's
I learn now like but I think that's a
huge thing that everybody should work on
because I think maybe other people I
know people who they learn by going to a
busy area like like Starbucks or
somewhere where there's other people
maybe like a part of this this may be
hard to get to right now at the current
quarantine but go go somewhere there's
other people we can hear background
noise mm-hmm grocery store if there's
like a little cafe in it you know
whatever you can hear in background and
they work well when they could hear
people other people in the background
they can think it focus they can flow
that pulls any way out of it so I find
the way that I learn I'm able to be here
and really envelop my whole like just
throw what I'm trying to envelop at my
face and just make sure I'm focused on
it if I was just headphones out like a
cafe maybe I wouldn't pay attention to
that because that's not how I learned so
mmm learn how you learn I guess it's
what I think yeah yeah that's I mean
that's what's crazy is the school system
it's not like that and so that's why
it's hard for a lot of people to learn
after they get at the school is because
you've literally been learning in a
general sense you're learning for the
masses and not for the individual you
know what I mean so it's it may not fit
everyone's cup of tea when it comes to
that style of learning so when you get
to the real world in your own life you
literally are uneducated on so much
because one they never taught you it in
school and two they never taught what
works best for your learning style
yeah willing grow you were punished for
not learning it their way yeah exactly
and then like not punished like beaten
but like literally say yeah no you have
to do it like this even though you're
like why wouldn't you do like this I got
to the same answer yeah
and it's just so insane that like you uh
you just get out of this you've never
had a chance before you could even start
because you go to a job and you're
literally like a hey I want to work for
you
they're like okay well like what was
your most recent you know degree or
diploma and you feel like that it's like
high school and say all right well now I
couldn't get to college because I've
literally couldn't understand absolutely
anything and they're like well we're
just gonna we only take college people
so even if you are good for the job and
you've learned like a trade itself like
you're just you didn't pass our
standards so it's just nuts like that
was really like that concept like like
like to crush someone you crush someone
so like was such a man like saying like
no no you can't be that like like
whatever you feel like you know can't be
that you happen to be this oh you're not
accepted yeah yeah and it's like what
you you want me to give a institution
one hundred thousand dollars to tell me
[__] that I could look up online and not
necessarily saying you wouldn't learn
anything new just saying that knowledge
is knowledge like it's an idea you're
making me pay $100,000 for an idea to
implement into my life and know it to be
true what like right a hundred thousand
just to make numbers round just for four
years of someone's developmental stages
in their life where they're not a kid
anymore at random and now have to be an
adult at random and say hey we're gonna
get you in debt for the rest of your
[__] life but we'll tell you what you
need to know to get a job to make sure
that you will maintain and never have
this debt consume you for the rest of
your life you know what a shackle bro
it's like watch bro I saw a boat I saw
you floating in the water could you hold
this Boulder for a second
yeah hold on to this I got it
here can you take this I got it trust me
it's all good this is the life that you
want us at the bottom like this is the
life that you dreamed about bro we don't
have to carry that man we can let go of
that Boulder and you can figure out what
works for you like like more than ever
like it because a lot of people are can
have a job right now like a lot of
people are the way that people are going
to reintroduce back into the world I
don't think it's going to be business as
usual I think that a lot more people may
have to or have the opportunity to like
explore like what do I want to do yeah
it's literally a time for people to
think like what's important to me like
what what gosh man like is it is making
two more dollars an hour worth me not
really vibing with my co-workers you
know like cuz I think that you know
maybe you got just a crazy bunch of
negative co-workers but you make that
extra moolah so you can buy more more
whatever on the weekend you know so I
don't know I guess that's skip to
forehead but I think that that you know
it gives time quick is a way that you
learn yeah yeah it's they're so quick
and once you get to a point where you
are consumed by like the everyday
thought and the mundane thought of like
I just have to go to work I have to make
the bills and like like it's just what
what I have to do to survive right now
like if I stop like my whole world would
be shaken I can't stop you know what I
mean and now that the world has stopped
before them they're like alright well
now what what are you gonna do like the
world is stopped yeah nobody needs you
right now like you literally like the
job that you do is not need it to
society at the moment like goddamn like
maybe I am like not as important to this
job as I would want to be or maybe like
I'm not happy going there every day this
I could just start afresh you know the
mean like I could literally start fresh
right now yeah okay okay so terrible you
know I was thinking it was such a sad
place for people to be in but I suppose
you're right
like it's a it's maybe maybe at first
it's sad because it's scary like geez
like what have I chosen yeah my life
like that that's a weird thing to like
ask yourself and because you can't
compare yourself there you can't compare
yourself to other people in a way you
compare yourself to you is directly
inside an you have to say like what am i
doing
not what what everybody else believes
like what like whatever else wants me to
do whatever else expects me to do if I'm
really doing what I what I think that I
want it like like one day I'm gonna I'm
gonna you know leave this world when you
do my a my heading towards the life that
I want to say that I have lived I kept I
really thought about that so I think
that it's a scary place to be but it's
also like you like you are inherently
optimistically wanting saying that that
it's a good thing it's a good spot to be
it's a it's a it's a strong spot to be
like and I think a lot of people who if
they haven't realized that they're there
maybe are going to be there or I don't
know I just think a lot of people are
gonna have a change of career right
about now if not coming soon and I don't
know if their careers are going to be
business as usual or if it's going to be
like more creators and more creative
sides of humanity are gonna be like you
know I'm gonna start that [__]
business because I have the power to buy
for whatever reason I don't know yeah
and I think it's nuts to that we're just
in a time where obviously like
technology is accelerating and
technology's taking on jobs and if
somehow this like implemented a lot of
like we don't know if there's like
talking all whoo here but we don't know
if they just said like hate your fight
or like ear fire temporarily from this
job but they still need some sort of
like accounting done or some sort of
thing done and they replace a computer
software program that does it ten times
faster than you and automates it like
holy [__] like I'm gonna come back and
they're back actually we don't need you
sorry that was a while and we couldn't
kind of we only expected you to be gone
for like two weeks but actually you were
gone for like two months we can't have
two months
worth of work not gone so we're just
gonna plug this program in and we've
been fine and we're saving money so why
wouldn't we do this as a business and
it's like that that's what people have
to actually start realizing now is that
hey this it's not a forever thing jobs
aren't a forever thing
it's literally getting to a point where
maybe some jobs are maybe for everything
but it's getting to a point where
they're taking up they're gonna be
taking up a lot of jobs in the future
we're becoming extremely intelligent
group of individuals on this planet like
monkeys of monkeys who are like [__]
with God powers you know they're really
suckers our spirits have been upgraded
yeah our spirit upgraded to this like I
mean the internet I can go on all day
about how insane mm-hmm it actually is
but we know many people could be looking
at the exact same thing at once
at once and you see people just to look
up anything at once like yeah anything
just to be able to communicate with you
right now and you're [__] miles and
miles and miles away in a real time an
hour and 15 minutes away like I can fly
my drone and see what I'm flying in real
time and know that like if a [__]
bird came to me I can move it real time
like right how how is that possible yeah
it's it's it's incredible like we've
advanced so much do you think I was
thinking about when you were talking
about jobs going away I think the that a
huge thing that people are gonna rub up
against is identity like we're gonna
have to rebirth all right then these
we're gonna have to like kind of like
reassign our Denny's and rebuild our
identities and re dig up like what the
the root of our seed shells really were
because our a lot of people that
entities are caught up in the Western
world are caught up with their job like
we are our job like hey what's up how
are you like I'm it's literally the
second thing like I'm Brandon Oh what do
you do I think that's who you are like
oh I'm a photographer yeah
I work in finance or oh I'm a business
salesman and then that leads the rest of
your conversation like the conversation
is contained within that box of what
that is like that but but regardless are
our identities are our default like our
comfort of who we know that we are like
we have formed our version of self
especially in the Western world and I
think I'm saying that because I hear it
said more often than like really knowing
I haven't really travelled around the
world much side thought but I just hear
it right but a either way our self our
identity the way that we live is
supremely wrapped up in our jobs our
career and where we're at on the edge of
like humanity is where like about to
take and kind of already have taken this
jump towards like hey like a crazy
amount of people are not going to be
lied enta phi with their job anymore
like like that's kind of like what
scares people about like you yeah and
then think about what it feels like
right now to not have a job and then
think like that's actually the same
feeling like that I'm gonna get when
this [__] does happen like you're
getting to experience what its gonna be
like to be abruptly not out of a job I
mean I'm pretty sure society will like
ease into it but it's inevitable like
we're the mass and the most of the
amount of people are on board to
progress technology and on board to just
like keep the [__] going cuz everyone's
like oh new iPhone like I'm taking that
like that's upgrading technology and
everyone in fields with shotguns yeah
there's definitely a fear that's where I
have to when I go to Lewis County when I
go to dress the back roads or anything
and I got some like real state gigs I'm
like oh [__] man I gotta watch out for
this drawn like this guy has like some
alpaca in a [__] Turkey and some pigs
and he's just sipping on a beer in his
front yard and I'm like flying this like
insane
drone just like you could just see him
like that's the future that's the
government I was telling you about
I thought Cindy I told you they were
watching me
just looking boom Carol that [__] Carol
that [__] I'm telling you it's it's
really like that lot of people are cool
and they understand that like that's a
technology coming out but some people
are reluctant to change especially out
and Louis cameos it sound terrifying for
them it goes against everything that
they believe in like if you think of of
the traditional like Christian like a
firm believer like Old Testament even
like the the stern like good people but
a lot of like the technology is starting
to really push into that beliefs like
you know I'm just that was a broad
example using Christians I suppose yeah
I'm just a really a lot of religion
overall a lot of fuels beliefs get like
weird and they're like that makes me
feel uncomfortable when like the super
big technology starts coming around
mm-hmm it's just like I didn't know the
question it like this okay mm-hmm and
it's it's nuts when you see like a
transformation in people to where like
they're super reluctant and they have a
flip phone still and then like a
Christmas comes around and their
significant other didn't know what they
need wanted to give them and they're
like oh I thought you wanted a new
iPhone so they give them one and then
they start using it and then they start
just becoming hooked on Facebook and
like hooked on all this [__] no my hair
I remember when you hated from like you
hated the technology and all the stuff
and now you're like look at this video
you know like watch this video we don't
understand it we didn't understand it
until you know it's not that we could
only understand it it's too late it's
but yeah we get pulled into things and
we can't really understand them
sometimes until it's like a
retrospective like oh okay I get it now
because I've I I have one now and I
found things that I like you know mm-hm
absolutely
that's nice man but I know that it has
been a long and fun podcast but life
probably has to start get going for me
on my home life at the moment so yeah
thank you for coming on and being the
dopest dopest man alive oh cool thanks
man that thanks for having me on
I this is super cool I like it
it's weird being interviewed I was
saying that like I have to turn off my
mind like I'm the mod cast host like
yeah well if you guys don't know he is a
host of jyl junkyard love podcast JY LP
so the deal at the Jill baby podcast
this thing is a journey in an experience
just getting able to listen to the
stories of some not only amazing people
but Jake and being able to bring on
these people and have such in-depth
conversations about life and knowledge
and wisdom and just being a human so if
you have not heard it I would definitely
say go check this out immediately before
you can listen to this or finish this
off turn it is this off I'm gonna finish
this off first and then go check it out
cuz it's awesome cool thanks for I
appreciate that
oh yeah thanks for having me I'll have
to do this more often I'm a Love You Man
yeah please yeah I guys say that too by
the way guys definitely say that - yeah
definitely definitely man look is that
all humans
you